Guide to the Colleccon of Many Learned Letters
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
"A colleccon of many learned letters"
1601-1650
OSBORN fb117
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.03
(1 volume)
Contemporary MS copies, in unknown hand.
Total Volumes: 1
Immediate Source of Acquisition
For provenance information, consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The following finding aid is a complete inventory of the contents of Osborn fb117. This list was reformatted from previously existing cataloging.
Courts and courtiers -- England; Nobility -- Conduct of life; Nobility -- England -- Correspondence; Great Britain -- Politics and government -- 1558-1603; Great Britain -- Social life and customs -- 16th century; Elizabeth, Queen of England, I, 1533-1603 -- Correspondence; Elizabeth, Queen of England, I, 1533-1603; Ellesmere, Thomas Egerton, Baron, 1540?-1617; Essex, Robert Devereux, Earl of, 1565-1601; Greville, Fulke, Baron Brooke, 1554-1628; Leicester, Robert Dudley, Earl of, 1532?-1588; Moryson, Fynes, 1566-1630; Moryson, Fynes, 1566-1630 ( Itinerary); Salisbury, Robert Cecil, Earl of, 1563-1612; Sidney, Philip, 1554-1586
- Osborn fb117
  - ARUNDEL, PHILIP HOWARD, 1ST EARL OF, 1557-1595
    - Letter to his father, Howard Thomas III, 4th Duke of Norfolk (1536-72)., n.d. (Box 1)
      Scope and Contents
      n.p.
      p. 1-2.
  - ARUNDEL, PHILIP HOWARD, 1ST EARL OF, 1557-1595
    - Letter to Sir Francis Walsingham (1530?-90)., n.d. (Box 1)
      p. 2-3.
  - ELIZABETH I, QUEEN OF ENGLAND, 1533-1603
    - 2 letters to Robert Devereux, 2nd Earl of Essex (1566-1601). (Box 1)
      [c.1598]
      Essex conspiracy papers.
      p. 3-4 and 9-12.
  - SIDNEY, SIR PHILIP, 1554-1586
    - Letter to Robert Sidney, 1st Earl of Leicester (1563-1626)., n.d. (Box 1)
      "A letter from Sr. Phillipp Sidney
      to his brother beinge beyond the
      seas."
      p. 4-8.
  - SALISBURY, ROBERT CECIL, 1ST EARL OF, 1563-1612
    - Letter to Robert Dudley, Earl of Leicester (1532?-88)., n.d. (Box 1)
      [1586 Nov 29]
      p. 13-14.
  - RICH, PENELOPE (DEVEREUX) RICH, LADY, 1562?-1607
    - Letter to Elizabeth I (1533-1603)., n.d. (Box 1)
      p. 14-16.
  - BROOKE, FULKE GREVILLE, 1ST BARON, 1554-1628
    - Letter to an unnamed recipient., n.d. (Box 1)
      p. 16-18.
  - ESSEX, ROBERT DEVEREUX, 2ND EARL OF, 1566-1601
    - Letter to Sir Thomas Egerton, Baron Ellesmere and Viscount Brackley (1540?-1617). (Box 1)
      [1598?]
      "The earle marshall to the Lords
      Keeper."
      p. 19-20.
  - EGERTON, SIR THOMAS, 1540?-1617
    - Letter to Robert Devereux, 2nd Earl of Essex (1566-1601). (Box 1)
      "The Lords Keeper to the Earle
      Marshall."
      p. 21-22.